sitedown.co 2018-12-28

# Privacy Policy | Site Down

Your privacy is critically important to us. At Site Down we have a few fundamental principles:

  * We don't ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (We can't stand services that ask you for things like your gender or income level for no apparent reason.)
  * We don't share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don't store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.
  * On our website, we aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what's visible to the public, seen by search engines, kept private, and permanently deleted.

Site Down (“ **Site Down** ”) operates several websites including [SiteDown.co](https://sitedown.co/). It is Site Down's policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Site Down collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Site Down may collect data from Interest-based advertising or 3rd-party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) for internal use. Site Down's purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Site Down's visitors use its website. From time to time, Site Down may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Site Down also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments. Site Down only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses and email addresses are visible and disclosed to administrators.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Site Down's websites choose to interact with Site Down in ways that require Site Down to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Site Down gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who comment on reports to provide a name and email address. Site Down collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor's interaction with Site Down. Site Down does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Aggregated Statistics

Site Down may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Site Down may monitor the most popular articles or use spam screened by the third party services to help identify spam. Site Down may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Site Down does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Site Down discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Site Down's behalf or to provide services available at Site Down's websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Site Down's websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Site Down will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Site Down discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when Site Down believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Site Down, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Site Down website and have supplied your email address, Site Down may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what's going on with Site Down and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Site Down takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

Site Down uses cookies to help identify and track visitors, their usage of the Site Down website, website access preferences, audience demographics and interests. Site Down visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Site Down's websites, with the drawback that certain features of Site Down's websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Site Down and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### Comments

Comments and other content submitted to our Akismet anti-spam service are not saved on our servers unless they were marked as false positives, in which case we store them long enough to use them to improve the service to avoid future false positives.

### Your Rights

If you are located in certain countries, including those that fall under the scope of the European General Data Protection Regulation (AKA the “GDPR”), data protection laws give you rights with respect to your personal data, subject to any exemptions provided by the law, including the rights to:

  * Request access to your personal data;
  * Request correction or deletion of your personal data;
  * Object to our use and processing of your personal data;
  * Request that we limit our use and processing of your personal data; and
  * Request portability of your personal data.

You can usually access, correct, or delete your personal data using your account settings and tools that we offer, but if you aren’t able to do that, or you would like to contact us about one of the other rights, scroll down to How to Reach Us to, well, find out how to reach us.

EU individuals also have the right to make a complaint to a government supervisory authority.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Site Down may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Site Down's sole discretion. Site Down encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

### Creative Commons License

This Privacy Policy is licensed under [Creative Commons Sharealike](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/).

This Privacy Policy has been re-purposed from Automattic Inc.'s Privacy Policy.
